[ The door 's open ]
[ Jum ] Sister ...
- [ Ratih ] What , Jum ? - Let 's go . I don 't ...
What ? You don 't want to bathe her ?
Jum , why are you , a Kliwon girl , scared ?
You were born on a Kliwon Friday , weren 't you ?
- Listen to me ... - Stop it !
Enough !
I feel hot here .
I 'm cleaning the house wearing this over-the-top clothing .
Let me change my clothes .
Sister , the recording 's broken .
What should I do ?
[ Thunder sound ]
What did you say ?
The recording 's broken .
[ Sigh ]
[ Raining sound ]
But have you finished the ritual ?
I haven 't .
- Not everything . - [ Sigh ]
- [ Raining ] - [ Sigh ]
Oh , dear !
[ Sigh ]
Come on ! Hurry !
Let 's go , Jum .
- [ Thunder sound ] - [ Interjection ]
What should we do , Jum ?
[ Sigh , foot steps sound ]
[ Door 's open ]
[ Door 's closed ]
[ Switching on light ]
[ Footsteps ]
Jum , come here .
Bring it back to the original position .
Hurry .
Lift it .
[ Thunder sound ]
Sister , her hand is blocking .
[ Footsteps ]
Her leg .
Put her leg inside .
- This one ? - Yes . Hurry .
Jum ?
Sister !
Sister Ratih !
[ Screaming ]
[ Hard blow ]
Sister !
[ Hard hit ]
[ Sobbed ]
[ Broken head ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Sigh ]
Who are you , child ?
- East Java , 2003 - [ Thunder sound ]
[ Bicycle sound ]
[ Footsteps ]
Job Vacancy : Female House Assistant , age 20-35
- Ma 'am . - Hey , Sri .
- Give this to Sister Minah , okay , Sri ? - Okay .
Yes . Hold on .
- Thank you , Sri . - Thank you , Ma 'am . Okay .
- Give my regards to Sister Minah . - Yes .
[ Bicycle sound ]
[ Minah ] Coffee for Mr. Budi .
[ Cutlery sound ]
Miss , I order sweet ice tea .
Alright .
- [ Sri ] Your coffee . Enjoy . - Thanks .
- These are done ? - Sri , the rawon !
Okay . One moment .
Excuse me .
Actually , I am feeling bad ,
especially because I haven 't paid the previous ones .
Thanks .
But I really need it , Sister .
[ Interjection ]
I 'm sorry , Sri .
But I also have a lot of expenses this month .
( Plates clinking )
Adi is starting school .
[ Pounding and cutting the meat sound ]
I have to buy books and uniform for him .
Hang on .
[ Scrape of paper sound ]
Here , Sri .
Try this .
Job Vacancy : Female House Assistant , age 20-35
Is this for the Atmojo family ?
Yes .
Weird .
They 're looking for helpers everyday .
The Atmojo family has a lot of restaurants .
Scattered all over Java .
That 's why they always need helpers .
They would pay you ten million rupiah , you know .
Who knows , maybe there will be a prince looking for a wife .
Do you think this is a soap opera ?
Miss , can I change my order to just water ?
You can . One moment , please .
Orange juice .
[ Clinking glass ]
[ Pouring water ]
Miss Sri ?
Yes ?
Do you have stingray mangut today ?
We have .
One moment , let me get it for you .
Sir ?
Sir !
What 's going on , Sri ?
He paid less money .
[ Interjection ]
That guy is fasting all white things .
He only consumes white rice and plain water .
I 'm okay with him fasting .
But he shouldn 't put us in a loss .
Let him be .
[ Thunder sound ]
[ Scrape of paper sound ]
[ Wind hissing ]
[ Sigh ]
[ Footsteps ]
- Miss , number three ? - Yes , Ma 'am ?
- Asmawati ? - Right .
- You brought your diploma ? - I did .
- Just prepare it . - Okay .
[ Bicycle sound , footsteps ]
Wati , I 'm a high school graduate , you know .
Why wouldn 't they accept me ?
- I don 't get it . - They really do have weird terms .
[ Raining ]
[ Screeching brake sound ]
[ Interjection ]
Miss ?
- Are you okay ? - I 'm fine .
Miss ? Are you okay ?
- Let me help ... - Ouch .
- Let 's get in . - I 'm fine .
Let 's just get in . Come on .
- Thank you , Miss . - Her bag .
[ Thunder sound ]
Hold it .
[ Sigh ]
[ Raining ]
- What 's your name , Miss ? - [ Thunder sound ]
Sri .
[ Interjection ]
I 'm Lydia .
Were you going to apply for a job here ?
I was , but then I changed my mind .
Why ?
I don 't have a diploma .
I see .
No diploma .
[ Door 's opening ]
It 's fine .
Hold one more second .
Done .
Take the bandage off at home .
Okay ?
Thank you .
No problem .
Lydia .
[ Interjection ]
One moment .
[ Footsteps ]
[ Thunder sound ]
Sri .
She wants to meet you .
Who ?
Mbah Karso .
She 's the head of the Atmojo family .
Hear me out , not everyone can meet her .
Who knows , maybe you 'll get hired instantly .
Let 's go .
[ Footsteps ]
Please , come in .
Come on .
[ Sigh ]
[ Footsteps ]
What 's your full name , child ?
Sri Rahayu .
You were born on a Kliwon Friday ?
How do you know ?
I can smell Wijoyo Kusumo and Gadru inside of you .
Why did you come here ?
My father , Mbah .
I need money for his medication .
[ Interjection ]
That means we want the same thing : to save our family .
You need money for your father 's medication .
And I need you to take care of my family .
I promise to help with your father 's medication .
But
you need to answer this first .
[ Sigh ]
Are you ready to work for me ?
[ Interjection ]
I 'm ready , Mbah .
[ Chairs creaking ]
[ Footsteps ]
After this
you cannot back out .
[ Footsteps ]
Follow me .
[ Sigh ]
[ Clanging ]
Come closer , Sri .
[ Footsteps ]
For now on , you are my servant .
With this , our agreement is approved .
Do your job
and I will do my part .
You cannot betray me .
Because your life has been pawned to me .
[ Pounding wooden furniture ]
Sri
please bathe my body with this water .
[ Interjection ]
[ Sigh ]
Feel my lesions , child .
I promise you
you will never have these kinds of lesions
as long as you keep your promise .
Wake up , Miss .
Miss ?
Wake up !
[ Car 's door open ]
Sorry , but what 's your name ?
Sugih .
Sri .
Mbah told me to tell you this .
Don 't tell anyone .
[ Car 's door closed ]
[ Vehicle sound ]
[ Coughing ]
I have a bad feeling about this .
Don 't you want to look for another place to work ?
[ Pouring water ]
[ Kettle sound ]
[ Cricket noises ]
What other place ?
We lost Tyas because we couldn 't pay .
[ Cricket noises ]
I don 't want to lose you because we don 't have money .
Okay then
if that 's what you want .
I 'm only going to tell you this .
Take care of yourself .
Sri ?
[ Coughing ]
What 's wrong ?
What 's going on here ?
Father ?
What 's wrong ?
What 's going on here ?
Sri !
Father !
[ Screaming ]
Sri !
[ Sigh ]
Drink your medication .
- I will . - And don 't forget to eat .
- Take rest . - Okay , child .
[ Coughing ]
[ Bird chirping ]
Okay , then .
Pray for me , father .
I surely will , child .
Take care .
[ Footsteps ]
[ Car 's door open ]
[ Car 's door closed ]
Hi , I 'm Sri , Miss .
Don 't call me Miss . We 're the same age .
I 'm Erna .
Miss .
[ Car 's door closed ]
Dini .
Don 't worry .
We all have the same markings .
It means Mbah has done the same thing to you .
Done what ?
How do you know ?
Miss Dini has worked for Atmojo family for a while .
[ Vehicle sound ]
Sorry , Sir .
Aren 't we going to Mbah Karso 's house ?
Where are we ?
Don 't get off the car .
[ Car 's door open ]
[ Interjection ]
[ Car 's door closed ]
[ Car 's door open ]
What 's going on here ?
Miss , what 's Mr. Sugih doing ?
[ Interjection ]
What is he doing ?
Oh , dear .
What 's going on there ?
[ Footsteps ]
[ Car 's door open ]
[ Car 's door closed ]
[ Interjection ]
Sorry , Sir .
What were you just doing ?
Nothing .
Don 't worry . We 'll get to our destination soon .
[ Vehicle sound ]
[ Car 's door open ]
[ Car 's door closed ]
Come on , Sri .
Is this also Mbah Karso 's house ?
Sri .
Thank you .
Thank you , Sir .
Just come in .
You 'll get an explanation later .
[ Footsteps ]
There 's no electricity here .
You have to turn on all the lights before it gets dark .
Your bedroom is over there .
Sri .
Day 1.000 ?
What 's on that day ?
We 're leaving on that day .
[ Interjection ]
- Mbah . - How was it ?
I 've done it as you ordered me to .
I 'm going to wait outside .
Okay .
I 'm Tamin .
You must be baffled
as to why you 're brought here .
The answer is
is in this room .
Now
wear this cloth .
Change your clothes with this .
Here ?
Come on .
That cloth
will protect you
because it has been soaked with water containing seven types of flowers
smoked
with incense
vetiver , and sandalwood .
The smell should
calm her down .
We 're done , Mbah .
Okay .
Okay , then .
Get the water from the pump in the kitchen .
Okay , Mbah .
[ Footsteps ]
[ Opening the padlock ]
Sorry if it smells bad .
It is the way it is .
Sri ...
Close the door , Din .
Okay .
Here are the batteries .
In the cassette
there 's a recording of Mbah Karso 's voice .
It contains the instruction
and steps for Bathing The Dead .
A ritual you have to do .
Bathe whom ?
Din ...
- ... open the cloth . - Okay .
[ Interjection ]
- That 's Della Atmojo . - [ Vomiting ]
The granddaughter of Mbah Karso Atmojo .
She 's a victim of strong dark magic .
Due to the dark magic
an evil being named Sangarturih is in her body .
It will stay inside of her for a thousand days .
If we do nothing
on day 1.000 , Della will be gone forever .
So , she can be saved by Bathing The Dead ritual ?
Bathing The Dead is only to calm Sangarturih .
For it not to be wild and harm others .
This ritual needs to be started when dusk begins .
And it needs to be done before the sun fully sets .
When it 's done
turn the cassette tape back to its original position .
Got it ?
Yes , Mbah .
Din .
Put the cassette on .
[ Playing the cassete ]
Thank you for helping me
to do the Bathing The Dead ritual .
I beg you to listen carefully and follow all my instructions .
Put some water into the basin .
After that
take the seven types of flowers .
Put a pinch of each according to the sequence .
First , red rose
white rose
jasmine
ylang-ylang
tuberose
white champak
and gambir .
Now
walk toward the bier .
Before opening the bier
make sure her hands and feet have been tied .
Start tying from her left feet and hands .
Open the bier 's covering
and put it on the right side of my granddaughter .
Don 't open the bier if my granddaughter isn 't tied .
Now , start washing from her feet
to her abdomen
to her face .
And then , her back .
Follow my words .
Humans are in this world for a reason .
Listen , you inhabitants of the world .
This is the reason I serve my master .
The glorious malicious breed .
Humans are in this world for a reason .
Listen , you inhabitants of the world .
This is the reason I serve my master .
The glorious malicious breed .
Humans are in this world for a reason .
Listen , you inhabitants of the world .
This is the reason I serve my master .
The glorious malicious breed .
[ Screaming ]
Humans are in this world ...
- ... for a reason . - [ Screaming ]
Evil human !
Sri !
Listen , you inhabitants of the world .
This is the reason I serve my master .
[ Thunder sound , raining ]
- Sri ? - Sri ?
- What 's wrong , Sri ? - Sri !
Help them inside !
Sri , are we allowed to leave ?
Sri !
- Where are you going ? - Home .
I can 't work like this .
But which direction is home ?
Hang on .
Oh , dear .
Sri !
Wait for me !
Wait for me , I 'm wearing a cloth .
Er ?
Er ...
My head .
[ Interjection ]
Blood .
[ Coughing ]
Erna ! Sri !
Sri ...
Sri , wake up .
Sri , Er .
Wake up .
Miss .
Drink this .
You fainted .
Are you better now ?
Sorry , children .
You have made an agreement with Mbah Karso .
And this place
has been fenced magically .
Not only to restrict Della .
But also to restrict you .
You only have to
bathe and take care of Della
for the next four days
until day 1.000 .
Got it ?
[ Door 's open ]
This will work , won 't it ?
[ Sigh ]
I hope so .
So , we can 't leave ?
We can .
[ Footsteps ]
[ Chair 's creaking ]
When our job is done .
I don 't get it .
Who would curse Della like that ?
The Atmojo family has a lot of enemies .
From what I heard
after she had been possessed by Sangarturih
Della killed her family
including her parents .
They had put her in a cage before she could kill Mbah Karso .
But it was before the Bathe The Dead ritual .
Since she has been given a bath
Della and Sangarturih can be controlled .
[ Sigh ]
Relax .
Don 't think too much .
We just need to help each other here now .
We are being paid well with ten million rupiah .
I have a family to feed .
I believe you have the same situation as me .
Remember your family .
Let 's just do our job .
This place is actually nice , Sri .
But inside ...
Horrifying .
Right .
It was really horrifying last night .
But do you think
Della is still
in there ?
Well
maybe .
But why didn 't they take her to the doctor ?
They have money .
Sri , Erna .
Let 's go pump the water .
Okay , Miss .
Sri , come on .
[ Pumping the well water ]
It 's hard .
[ Running water sound ]
The pump is here .
[ Pumping , running water sound ]
Then you put the water in the basin .
In the room , you mix it with the seven types of flowers .
[ Pumping , running water sound ]
The sequence ...
Just follow Mbah Karso 's instruction from the cassette .
Who will help me bathe Della this evening ?
[ Bird 's chirping ]
I 'll do it .
Okay , then .
[ Footsteps ]
[ Interjection ]
Try it .
Me or you ?
You first .
[ Cricket noises ]
[ Footsteps ]
Help , Miss .
Miss ?
Help me , Miss .
Sri ?
[ Interjection ]
[ Footsteps ]
I heard Della 's voice from the room .
Ignore it .
That 's Sangarturih , not Della .
We have a problem .
The pump is jammed .
Without water , we can 't bathe Della .
We can 't cook .
[ Sigh ]
[ Interjection ]
Er ...
Yes , Miss ?
Can you bathe Della by yourself ?
By myself ?
[ Clink bucket ]
Just follow the instructions from the recording .
Wear the batik cloth .
Now , before the sun sets .
Okay , Miss .
Er .
Don 't do it wrong .
Yes , Miss .
You help me .
What should I do ?
[ Birds ' chirping ]
Humans are in this world for a reason .
Listen , you inhabitants of the world ...
Sri , find a bolt like this one in the toolbox .
Yes , Miss .
[ Footsteps ]
Humans are in this world for a reason .
Listen , you inhabitants of the world .
This is the reason I serve my master .
Humans are in this world for a reason ...
[ Thunder sound , raining ]
998 Days
[ Raining ]
[ Closing window ]
[ Footsteps ]
[ Thunder sound ]
[ Sigh ]
Miss !
Help me !
[ Cry out ]
[ Gasping for breath ]
[ Interjection ]
Sri ?
You 're awake ?
What 's wrong with you ?
Why do you look so pale ?
I 'm fine .
[ Interjection ]
Thank God .
Miss Dini wanted to wake you up .
But I told her to let you sleep .
Because you looked tired .
Let 's have breakfast .
Come on .
How could it be ?
Did you see who that was ?
No , Er .
I had just woken up .
Miss .
Is there any sugarcane field around here ?
I don 't know .
And I heard someone asking for help
from inside the shack .
Is that so ?
It sounded like Della 's voice .
[ Interjection ]
What does that mean ?
[ Chewing sound ]
It could be nothing .
You couldn 't stop thinking about it , so you dreamt about it .
[ Interjection ]
But
this leaf .
Why was it on the bed ?
Stop it !
We just have to work for two more days .
Don 't have weird thoughts .
Sri .
You will bathe Della this evening ?
[ Interjection ]
That means I can rest .
You 'll help me clean up this place .
Yes , Miss .
[ Door 's open ]
[ Clink bucket ]
[ Interjection ]
[ Door 's closed ]
[ Wooden matches sound ]
... to her abdomen
to her face .
And then , her back .
[ Tape button sound ]
Thank you for helping me do the Bathing The Dead ritual .
I beg you to listen ...
Miss .
What 's your name , Miss ?
My name 's Sri .
Della ?
I can hear
your voice and the others ' .
But now
I can only lie down .
My little sister also loved to sleep .
Sleepyhead .
[ Smirking ]
Your little sister , what 's her name ?
Tyas .
Where is she now ?
Gone .
Oh , gone .
I 'm so sorry , Miss .
Let me bathe you , okay ?
Miss Sri .
Can you come closer ?
I want to see the face of the person who is taking care of me .
I had a dream last night .
I think you were in my dream , Del .
I
for helping me ...
Open the bier 's covering .
... for helping me ...
You can untie the rope .
Open the bier 's covering .
[ Wooden matches sound ]
[ Thunder sound ]
[ Blowing up the candle light ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Wooden matches sound ]
Miss .
I 'm scared .
Come here .
Sri .
I 'm scared .
[ Crying out ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Screaming ]
Sri !
- What 's wrong ? - Miss Della !
Hang on , let me wear my cloth .
Wait for me .
Why couldn 't you do this easy task ?
[ Door 's closing ]
I swear .
I swear , the tape was playing strangely .
I was told to open the bier .
The flowers were scattered .
And Della ...
You must 've heard it wrong !
Remember what I told you this morning !
Don 't have weird thoughts !
Just do your job well !
Er , did you bathe her correctly ?
[ Thunder sound ]
I did .
From start to finish
nothing weird with Della .
What 's going on ?
- Tadi Della ... - Cukup !
No need to talk about it !
Sri ...
What 's going on here ?
Complicated .
[ Footsteps ]
[ Thunder sound ]
Oh dear !
999 Days
Help !
Miss !
[ Sigh ]
Help !
[ Interjection ]
Miss !
Help !
[ Gasping ]
[ Knocking the door ]
Excuse me .
[ Knocking ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Birds ' chirping sound ]
[ Footsteps ]
[ Sigh ]
How 's it going , Din ?
Anything weird happened when I was away ?
I 'll tell you about it .
Please help me unload .
Yes , Mbah .
Good morning , Mr. Sugih .
What 's that for ?
There 's something I need to do .
Just a moment .
It 's okay if it takes longer .
We 're happy to have you here .
[ Laughing ]
Let 's go , Sri .
[ Digging ]
It 's been a while .
What is he digging for ?
Until this late in the afternoon .
I don 't know .
It looks like he 's looking for something .
[ Digging ]
Mbah .
Here 's the thing ...
Yesterday
the voice in the tape changed .
It told me to set Della free .
[ Interjection ]
Dini had told me .
That was Sangarturih 's doing .
It will do anything
to be free .
Including tricking you .
Not only that .
I also had weird dreams twice .
What dream ?
I was
at a sugarcane field .
I found a shack .
[ Interjection ]
I heard a voice inside , sounded like Della 's .
And then someone attacked me .
[ Smirking ]
Relax .
Don 't think too much about it .
The important thing is you 're okay .
- But ... - Only one more day , Sri .
And then you can go home .
That 's all you need to think about .
Okay ?
[ Door 's open ]
Sri .
Let 's open it .
Don 't be impudent !
It 's ok , Miss .
You 're also curious about what 's inside , right ?
Right ?
Come on .
Okay .
One , two , three .
[ Interjection ]
[ Pumping the well water ]
It 's still broken .
Sri ...
Slow down .
It 's jammed .
It 's enough .
[ Sigh ]
What are they planning , Er ?
I don 't know .
But if we have the chance
we leave .
But we 'll end up just like the other day .
Well
it 's okay . Bear it .
When we reach the city , we 'll go to a witch doctor .
Okay ?
You 've filled the bucket ?
We have .
[ Interjection ]
Take note , Sri .
Don 't make a mistake again .
Okay .
You can do it .
Come on , Sri . It 's late .
[ Open the padlock ]
[ Door 's open ]
[ Clink bucket ]
[ Wooden matches sound ]
Start washing from her feet
to her abdomen ...
Here , Miss .
It was exactly like this yesterday .
Why is it so ?
Start again from the beginning , then .
Thank you for helping me do the Bathing The Dead ritual .
I beg you to listen carefully and follow all my instructions .
Don 't screw up the sequence .
Miss , the bucket 's leaking .
You 're right !
Oh , dear .
Sri , get some more water !
- It 's late ! - Okay .
I 'll be on the lookout here .
[ Footsteps ]
What 's wrong with you ?
[ Interjection ]
[ Pumping ]
What should I do ?
Sri !
Hang on !
[ Pumping ]
Damn it !
Before opening the bier ...
Just go . Let me keep watch here .
You help Sri .
Okay , then .
Keep watch here , okay ?
[ Pumping ]
Hang on !
Again !
Enough .
Come on , Sri !
Close the door .
[ Door 's closed ]
[ Interjection ]
[ Crying ]
Del ...
Della ...
[ Sobbed ]
Candle .
[ Wooden matches sound ]
Del ?
[ Crying out ]
[ Screaming ]
Miss Dini ! Sri !
[ Gasping ]
What happen ?
Where 's Della , Sri ?
Are you okay ?
Where 's Della ?
A Kliwon child !
[ Screaming ]
Della !
[ Pouring water ]
[ Gasping ]
This is the reason I serve my master .
The glorious malicious breed .
You were all born on Kliwon day .
You 're all
only human sacrifices .
Humans are in this world for a reason .
Listen , you inhabitants of the world .
This is the reason I serve my master .
The glorious malicious breed .
1.000 Days
It hurts , Miss .
How could you not hear Della leaving ?
What were you doing at the door ?
This has been weird all along !
The tape started from the middle . The bucket leaked .
What did I say , Sri ?
Be thorough !
If we 're not thorough , we 'll be doomed !
We 've been doomed since we came here !
[ Sobbed ]
You were all born on a Kliwon Friday ?
What , Er ?
Didn 't you hear ?
Della said we 're only human sacrifices .
[ Gasping ]
I think ...
I think we were sacrificed by Mbah Tamin .
To replace Della 's life .
And who is that grave at the front for ?
For us !
Oh , God !
Enough !
When Della was still at Mbah Karso 's house
I worked there with my friends .
Jum and Ratih .
They made a mistake
and didn 't finish the ritual .
They were killed by Della .
It made me abandon my husband .
And my kid .
I tried to kill myself .
Thankfully , Mbah Tamin came along .
He saved me .
He said my life is precious .
I have to live .
And that he had a way to save me .
He only had one condition !
I had to help out until day 1.000 !
I believe him !
[ Sobbed ]
And I ask
that you believe too !
[ Crying ]
[ Pouring water ]
[ Interjection ]
Del ?
[ Door 's open ]
[ Interjection ]
Del ?
See ?
I told you we should 've left .
[ Thunder sound ]
I don 't want to die yet !
What are you talking about , Er !
Calm down !
We have a responsibility here .
To keep a watch on Della . To not let her loose .
Stop it , Er !
We can 't !
Mbah Tamin said this area has been fenced .
That 's right . The fence .
You 're right , Sri .
Della should still be around here .
Mbah Tamin said the fence is in the shape of a Corpse Umbrella .
There are three of them .
We need to make sure all of them are still stuck on the ground .
[ Thunder sound ]
[ Gasping , raining ]
[ Screaming , groaning ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Screaming ]
It 's time for you to die !
Della !
[ Coughing ]
[ Stabbing ]
[ Screaming ]
Erna ?
Er ? What are you doing Er ?
Er !
Erna ?
Er ?
[ Screaming ]
What 's wrong with you ?
I have to do this , Sri .
I need to pull out all of those umbrellas !
But why ?
Our job is to keep a watch on Della .
I am here to let her go .
Mbah Karso started all this .
You will not understand .
This is the reason ...
Be Mbah Karso servant !
This is the reason I serve my master .
The glorious malicious breed .
The bucket is leaking
[ Opening the padlock ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Raining ]
Er ?
Erna ?
Er ...
[ Screaming , crying ]
Er !
[ Crying ]
I get that you regret what you were doing .
But it was self-defense .
If you didn 't do it
you wouldn 't be here now .
Just one more day , Sri .
You 'll be able to meet your father tonight .
Erna 's gone .
She 's gone .
[ Sobbing ]
I 'm leaving now .
[ Footsteps ]
Sri .
[ Sobbed ]
I killed Erna .
Erna is dead .
But trust me
it 's not your fault .
Too many lives have been lost in this mess .
Let Erna be the last .
I know you had a sister .
And when she was gone , you were helpless .
But now you have power .
You can save Della .
What can I do , Mbah ?
I 'm a nobody !
Only your blood has the scent of Wijoyokusumo and Arum Gadru .
Just like Sabdo Kuntjoro , the sender of this black magic .
What you experienced in your sleep wasn 't a dream .
It was the world of Sukma .
That 's where Della is held captive .
[ Sigh ]
And during these 1.000 days
you 're the first person who has been in contact with her .
You 're the only one who can go there , Sri .
And you can save Della only today .
I beg you
don 't let all this effort go to waste .
Help my granddaughter , Sri .
She 's the only family I have left .
[ Gasping ]
Din , while Sri enters the world of Sukma ...
... don 't stop the Bathing The Dead ritual .
Keep Sangarturih calm .
Got it ?
Start now .
Okay , Mbah .
You and Della will be bound to each other .
Find Della .
And bring her here .
To this grave .
Bring this to the world of Sukma .
Sabdo Kuntjoro will stop you there .
Sri ...
Bring back my granddaughter .
She 's the only family I have left .
One more thing .
The world of Sukma is different from our world .
When it 's day here , it 's night there .
You have only until before the sun rises there .
When the day comes , the 1,000th day ends
and Della won 't be able to be saved anymore .
Got it ?
Surrender yourself , Sri .
Humans are in this world for a reason .
Listen , you inhabitants of the world .
This is the reason I serve my master .
The glorious malicious breed .
Sri , you will be okay .
Surrender yourself , Sri
Close your eyes .
[ Screaming ]
[ Gasping ]
Miss .
Della ?
I can 't take it anymore here .
Help me , Miss .
[ Smashing the door ]
Miss !
Help me , Miss .
[ Smashing the door ]
Mbah , I ran out of water .
Mbah !
- [ Screaming ] - Dini !
Della !
- Tamin . - [ Hit the head hardly ]
Della don 't do it .
Tamin .
- Della . - Miss !
I 'm over here , Miss !
- Della . - I can 't take it anymore here .
I feel like I want to die .
- Della ? - Find the key , Miss .
Where 's the key ?
He usually brings it with him .
Who are you talking about ?
[ Screaming ]
[ Gasping ]
Miss , the key , please .
Find it , Miss .
Come on , Miss .
Miss !
Don 't open the door !
[ Door 's open ]
[ Door 's closed ]
Della ?
Miss ?
I 'm Sri .
Hang on .
[ Screaming ]
Della .
Now , it 's your time !
Remember whom you serve .
You 're ready to die by the hands of ...
Sangarturih ...
You are my children
until you 're the only one left
took you from me .
Remember .
Miss Sri .
We can 't be long here .
Come on .
[ Screaming ]
Don 't take her .
Damn you !
Della ! Let 's go !
Del !
Della ! You can 't go anywhere , Del !
Del ! You can 't go anywhere !
Del ! You can 't ! Del !
Della !
Damn you !
Del !
Oh , God !
Come on , Del !
Miss Sri .
Miss .
Come on , Del !
[ Gasping ]
Miss Sri !
[ Screaming ]
- Del ! - Miss .
Get up .
Come on .
Damn you !
[ Gasping ]
Miss Dini .
Miss !
- Sri ! - Miss Dini ...
Della ?
- Della ? - Mbah ?
It 's me , your grandmother .
Mbah !
[ Sobbing ]
Come . Stand up .
[ Interjection ]
Miss Sri .
We 're leaving .
Del .
Della .
[ Crying ]
[ Vomiting ]
My Dear ...
Atmojo the killer .
[ Door 's open ]
Sabdo Kuntjoro ...
Where 's your promise ?
Sri ?
[ Footsteps ]
How are you , child ?
I 'm so sorry
that you had to become like this to save my granddaughter .
Sri .
As I promised .
We 're even now .
Take it .
You deserve it .
Mbah .
Is it true
that you started all this ?
I once heard an ancient proverb
that
knowledge can bring you to death .
The longer I live
the more I understand what it means .
You
cannot know more than this .
Because ignorance is God 's gift .
Keep your money .
I 'll take my leave .
[ Raining ]
[ Interjection ]
[ Car 's door closed ]
[ Car 's engine started ]
[ Raining ]
Sri .
The money from Mbah Karso ...
You didn 't take it ?
It 's the right decision .
If you had taken it , you would end up like me .
But you need to be careful .
Mbah Karso will force you to take that money .
How do you know about all of this ?
Sabdo Kuntjoro
was my master .
The last I heard was he got away .
But that 's why
he survived this bloody affair .
He was very sad when he lost all of his family .
All of his family ?
What do you mean ?
All of the Kuntjoro family is dead because of black magic
sent by Atmojo family .
The Black Leaf magic .